PRABHPREET SINGH

14216 88th Avenue Surrey, BC V3W 3L7

<u>prabhpreetsingh013@gmail.com</u> Portfolio: <u>prabhsembhi.github.io/Personal_Portfolio</u>

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS AND SKILLS

Computer Studies and Information Systems (diploma), graduate, passionate to learn new technology. Attained over 4 years of customer service experience in Front desk services and office assistance with proven ability of strategic planning and significant verbal & written communication

Key Skills:

- Proficient in HTML, CSS, JAVASCRIPT
- Proficient in data query language (SQL and NoSQL)
- Hands on experience deploying Web sites.
- Using Frameworks and libraries including BOOTSTRAP, REACTJS, NODEJS
- Knowledgeable about the agile environment and sprint concepts
- Strong mediation and problem solving

EDUCATION

Diploma in Computer Studies and Information Systems

January 2018-December 2019

Douglas College, New Westminster, BC

•Relevant courses: Java, C#, Web Development, PHP, AJAX, Data Structures, Database Basic and Advanced, Mobile Development (using Android Studio, Google Cloud, and AWS), Networking, Virtualization, Network Security, Software Engineering, System Analysis and Design, Business mathematics, Corporate Finance, Marketing, Macro-economics

PROJECTS

Project 1: Buddies Android App

A replica for Meetup app currently in market.

In my part, I worked in implementing Google Login API and oauth2

Google Maps API: allowing to see live location of users.

Firebase Realtime database: for implementing and storing live chat and location

Project 2: Classic Café

A website for a local café.

In my part, Creating Maven Project using JAVA in Eclipse.

Structure the **Spring MVC** model and demonstrated its implementation to my team

Structured the Git repository and demonstrated my team the use of Gitbash and Hyper Terminal

Send and Retrieve data from MS ACCESS Database

Project 3: Keeper Website

A replica for Google Keep, website for keeping notes.

Creating React App Project using nodejs and reactjs

Used props, Components and Hooks for implementation

Potential to make use of Google login and save data in Firebase in Google Cloud

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Security Concierge at Telus Garden Offices

June 2018- Till Date

ROLES & RESPONSIBILITIES:

- Using the LENEL system for the security solution implementation.
- Responding to questions with a solution while maintaining the priority sequence
- Supporting the manager in all the tasks required
- Stepping in during managers absence.

Office Assistant at Ishwar Mechanical Works

January 2016- October 2018

ROLES & RESPONSIBILITIES:

- Maintain client database, secure confidential files and forward documents to select recipients
- Schedule staff and organize orders as per priority
- Keen attention to detail ensuring the accurate completion of multiple tasks by strict deadlines
- Update suppliers' transaction database and reviews invoices forwarded by the accounting office
- Arrange appointments and meetings
- Analyzed purchase orders, monitored delivery status and updated customers on their orders.

AWARDS & ACHIEVEMENTS

- Published technical blogs https://prabhsembhi.blogspot.com/
- Received teacher's recognition for creating the best android app project
- Gained Corporal Rank in school level military training